gamedev.tv 2019-04-19

# Privacy Policy — GameDev.tv

Thank you for joining us. We at GameDev.tv respect your privacy and want you to understand how we collect, use, and share data about you.

When we say “we,” “us,” “our,” and “GameDev.tv,” we are referring to Embrace IT Ltd, a UK limited liability company.

This Privacy Policy covers our management of personally identifiable data that we collect when you use our site, sign up for updates or use our services. We take your privacy extremely seriously, and we never sell lists or email addresses.

We may change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy.

## What we collect

We may request and hold the following information:

### Mailing List

  * Name
  * Email address
  * Location – city, postcode

### Website

  * Blog comments
  * Cookies
  * IP address
  * Website usage data

We may collect this personally identifiable information when you use our website. We also automatically receive and record information about the ways people visit and interact with our Site, in the form of traffic analytics. You can [opt out of being included in Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

### Forum

  * Information that you submit on or to GameDev.tv in the form of comments, contributions to discussions, or messages to other users
  * The email address associated with your social login (Facebook, Twitter, Google or GitHub). We never post anything to your Facebook, Twitter, or other third-party accounts.

### Udemy

  * As a student on any of our courses we have access to data in relation to these courses such as reviews, comments, course progress.
  * We adhere to [Udemy's privacy policy](https://www.udemy.com/terms/privacy/).

## How we use data

We use your data to:

  * Provide the website functionality, including to display customized content and facilitate communication with other users.
  * Provide answers and guidance to users and students.
  * Improve the content of our courses and the services we provide around them.
  * Analyse purchasing behaviours to develop better offers.
  * Moderate content and ensure the safety of our users.
  * Send you emails, if opted into our mail list.

We have never, and will never, sell or rent your personal data to a third party. We only share your data with third party’s required to provide our service. These are outlined below.

We will only ever send personally identifiable information about to you other companies when:

  * We respond to court orders or legal processes.
  * We find that your actions on our website or by any other communication violate our Terms and Conditions or any of our usage guidelines for specific products of services. For example, when we need to pass your details onto our lawyer.

Mail list subscribers: When you have opted into our mail list via the sign-up form, we store the information you provide in our email marketing database on [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/). We'll only use your information with your consent, and for the following reasons:

  * Sending information about GameDev.tv projects (such as new courses, Kickstarters and other news)
  * Internal record keeping

We use several third party providers for hosting:

  * Discourse (our forum)
  * WPEngine (our blog)
  * SquareSpace (our website)
  * [LeadCycle](https://leadcycle.co.uk/) and Facebook (for marketing)
  * Google Analytics (for traffic research)

## Accuracy and Retention of Data

We do our best to keep your data accurate and up to date, to the extent that you provide us with the information we need to do so. If your data changes (for example, if you have a new email address), then you are responsible for notifying us of those changes. Upon request, we will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your Personal Information.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as long as needed to provide you with our Services. We may also retain and use your information in order to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent abuse, and enforce our Agreements.

## Removing your data from our records

We will never use your data without your permission, and you are always able to control how we use your data.

  * There will always be an unsubscribe link in our emails, which will instantly unsubscribe you from further communications. Your data is still stored (but not used) in our Mailchimp database, to ensure we do not email you in the future.
  * If you have previously agreed to us using your personal data for marketing purposes you can contact us to change this. Email us at [info@GameDev.tv](mailto:info@GameDev.tv) to request your data to be removed from our databases.
  * You can delete your forum account (or ask us to it). If you have posts dating back more than 6 months, then your account will anonymised rather than deleted. This means the posts will still exist but none of your personal data is retained.

If you have any questions about your data please email us at [info@GameDev.tv](mailto:info@GameDev.tv).

## Security

All of the personal data we use and control is encrypted and stored securely to prevent unauthorised access. Our website has an SSL certificate which will secure the connection between the browser and our website. Seeing ‘https’ in your browser address bar shows you that our SSL certificate is active.

## Children

We recognize the privacy interests of children and encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Children under 13 should not register for an account or use our Services. If we learn that we’ve collected personal data from a child under those ages, we will take reasonable steps to delete it. 

If you believe that a child has provided us with personal information, please contact us at [info@GameDev.tv](mailto:info@GameDev.tv). If we become aware that a child under age 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information, we’ll delete it.

## Cookies

We may set and access cookies on your computer and we may gather information about your general internet use by using the cookie. These cookies are downloaded to your computer and stored on the computer’s hard drive. This data does not identify any personal details about you whatsoever, unless you are authenticating with our service.

You can adjust the settings on your computer to decline any cookies if you wish. This can be done by activating the 'reject cookies' setting on your computer.

[Find out more about cookies](http://www.whatarecookies.com/) and how to adjust your settings.

## Ask a question

We hope our privacy policy has been useful to you. If you have any further questions please contact us at [info@GameDev.tv](mailto:info@GameDev.tv).
